Guide to the Robert E. Butts Papers, 1908-1997 ASP.2000.01
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Professional Materials, 1951-1997; II.
  - Professional Organizations and Conferences, 1963-1997; 3.
    - Conferences, 1969-1996; 2.
      - 2nd International Conference on History and Philosophy of Science, 1973-1980 (Box 18, Folder 8)
      - Hunt Workshop in History of Science (Box 18, Folder 9)
      - Materials Related to Miscellaneous and Unidentified Professional Conferences (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Research and Writing by Others, 1967-1997; 4.
    Butts played an active role as a colleague and friend to other researchers and academics in his field. He was sought after as a reviewer of academic publications and grant proposals as well as a reference for colleagues and students. The material in Section 1, which consists of applications, CVs, and correspondence, documents these functions. Both subgroups in this subseries are arranged by individual's surname, though Section 2 consists of unpublished drafts rather than administrative materials.
    - References and Reviews, 1967-1997; 1.
      The items in this section are arranged by individual. Each individual's file may contain a variety of documents pertaining to Butts' role as a mentor and referee for his students and colleagues in their careers and publishing endeavors. This includes reference and referee requests, as well as applications, CVs/resumes, manuscripts, proposals, and any other material that may have been enclosed with Butts' correspondence on the subject. Note that all letters of reference and personally identifiable or confidential information have been removed and restricted.
      - Arthur, Richard, 1982 (Box 18, Folder 11)
      - Amerik, Karl, 1982 (Box 18, Folder 12)
      - Anderson, Abraham, 1994 (Box 18, Folder 13)
      - Baigrie, Brian, 1982 (Box 18, Folder 14)
      - Bakan, Mildred B., 1990 (Box 18, Folder 15)
      - Brown, James Robert, 1982-1986 (Box 18, Folder 16)
      - Bush, C.M. Anastasia, 1982 (Box 18, Folder 17)
      - Chokr, Nadr N. (Box 18, Folder 18)
      - Collier, John, 1983 (Box 18, Folder 19)
      - Curtis, R.C., 1983 (Box 18, Folder 20)
      - Denis, Francois-Michel, 1982 (Box 18, Folder 21)
      - DiSalle, Robert, 1995 (Box 18, Folder 22)
      - Donovan, Arthur, 1984 (Box 18, Folder 23)
      - Edwards, Paul, 1967 (Box 18, Folder 24)
      - English, Parker, 1982-1986 (Box 18, Folder 25)
      - Falkenstein, Lorne, 1986 (Box 18, Folder 26)
      - Forster, Paul D., 1994 (Box 18, Folder 27)
      - Foss, Jeffrey E., 1982-1983 (Box 18, Folder 28)
      - Friedman, Michael (Box 18, Folder 29)
      - Notes on the Work of Michael Friedman, 1984-1989 (Box 18, Folder 30)
      - Gauthier, Yvon, 1981-1982 (Box 18, Folder 31)
      - Good, Gregory Alan, 1983 (Box 18, Folder 32)
      - Hahlweg, Kai, 1980-1986 (Box 18, Folder 33)
      - Hanson, Norwood Russell (Box 18, Folder 34)
      - Hattiangadi, Jagdish N., 1985 (Box 18, Folder 35)
      - Hudson, Robert G. (Box 18, Folder 36)
      - Jobe, Evan K., 1990 (Box 18, Folder 37)
      - Johnstone, Albert A., 1982 (Box 18, Folder 38)
      - Khalidi, Muhammed Ali, 1996 (Box 18, Folder 39)
      - Kitcher, Patricia, 1990 (Box 18, Folder 40)
      - Laudan, Larry, 1982 (Box 18, Folder 41)
      - Lauxterman, P.F.H. (Box 18, Folder 42)
      - Lennon, Thomas M., 1983 (Box 19, Folder 1)
      - Levy, Edwin, 1982 (Box 19, Folder 2)
      - Lugg, Andrew (Box 19, Folder 3)
      - Malik, Muhammed Abdul, 1988 (Box 19, Folder 4)
      - Manukian, Edward, 1983 (Box 19, Folder 5)
      - Meerbote, Ralf, 1979 (Box 19, Folder 6)
      - Mukherjee, Ramkrishna (Box 19, Folder 7)
      - Nickles, Thomas, 1982 (Box 19, Folder 8)
      - Niiniluoto, Ilkka (Box 19, Folder 9)
      - Po-Keeing, 1986 (Box 19, Folder 10)
      - Rescher, Nicholas, 1991-1997 (Box 19, Folder 11)
      - Rothbart, David, 1984 (Box 19, Folder 12)
      - Ruse, Michael (Box 19, Folder 13)
      - Sassen, Brigitte, 1993 (Box 19, Folder 14)
      - Savage, Wade, 1984 (Box 19, Folder 15)
      - Shea, William, 1986-1987 (Box 19, Folder 16)
      - Stevens, Wesley M., 1988 (Box 19, Folder 17)
      - Wilson, David B., 1983 (Box 19, Folder 18)
      - Unidentified Research Proposals (Box 19, Folder 19)
      - Miscellaneous Referee Requests, Work or Author Not Specified (Box 19, Folder 20)
      - Administrative Materials and Correspondence re: Refereeing (Box 19, Folder 21)
    - Unpublished Drafts by Others, 1968-1996; 2.
      - Agassi, Joseph, "Science is Real and Ideal: Popper and the Dogmatic Scientist" (Box 19, Folder 22)
      - Alavoutunki, Jouni, "An Introduction to the Study of History of Science at the University of Konstanz", 1976 (Box 19, Folder 23)
      - Arthur, Richard, "Pacidius to Philalethes: First Philosophy of Motion, by G.W. Leibniz" (translation) (Box 19, Folder 24)
      - Barnes, Barry and Bloor, David, "Relativism, Rationalism, and the Sociology of Knowledge", 1980 (Box 19, Folder 25)
      - Beck, Lewis White, "Kant on the Uniformity of Nature" (Box 19, Folder 26)
      - Belsey, Andrew, "Whewell on Induction", 1971 (Box 19, Folder 27)
      - Bencivenga, Ermanno, "Knowledge as a Relation and Knowledge as an Experience in the Critique of Reason" (Box 19, Folder 28)
      - "Berkeley's Master Argument: Appearance and Reality," author unknown (Box 19, Folder 29)
      - Bohme, Gernot, "Kants Begriff der Materie in Seiner Schrift 'Metaphysische Anfangsgrunde der Naturwissenschaft'" (Box 19, Folder 30)
      - Bohme, Gernot, "Kant's Epistemology as a Theory of Alienated Knowledge" (2 drafts) (Box 19, Folder 31)
      - Bradie, Michael, "Models and Metaphors in Science: The Metaphorical Turn" (Box 20, Folder 1)
      - Brittan, Gordon, "Kant's Two Grand Hypotheses" (Box 20, Folder 2)
      - Brittan, Gordon, "The Kantian Foundations of Modern Science" (Box 20, Folder 3)
      - Brown, James Robert, "Einstein's Principle Theorems", 1995 (Box 20, Folder 4)
      - Brown, James Robert, "Theories of Method and Historical Evidence", 1979 (Box 20, Folder 5)
      - Brown, James Robert, "Rescher's Evolutionary Epistemology", 1982 (Box 20, Folder 6)
      - Brown, James Robert, "Thought Experiments Since the Scientific Revolution", 1986 (Box 20, Folder 7)
      - Brown, Jim, "Comments on the Occasion of the Presentation of An Intimate Relation to Robert E. Butts" (Box 20, Folder 8)
      - Buchdahl, Gerd, "Kant's 'Special Metaphysics' and the Metaphysical Foundations of Natural Science" (3 drafts) (Box 20, Folder 9)
      - Buchdahl, Gerd, "A Logical Articulation of Kant's Transcendental Structure" (Box 20, Folder 10)
      - Buchdahl, Gerd, "A Key to the Problem of Affection" (Box 20, Folder 11)
      - Buroker, Jill Vance, Reviews of Her Space and Incongruence: The Origin of Kant's Idealism (Box 20, Folder 12)
      - Carrier, Martin, "What is Wrong With the Miracle Argument?", 1990 (Box 20, Folder 13)
      - Carrier, Martin, "Kants Theorie der Materie und ihre Wirkung auf die zeitgenössische Chemie" (Box 20, Folder 14)
      - Copp, David and Levy, Edwin, "Value Neutrality in the Techniques of Policy Analysis: Risk and Uncertainty", 1982 (Box 20, Folder 15)
      - Dickens, Charles, "Old Lamps For New Ones" (typescript) (Box 20, Folder 16)
      - Doering, Michael, "Consilience as a Mark of True Theories" (Box 20, Folder 17)
      - Dryer, D.P., "On Two Arguments for the Principle of Causality Said to be Found in Kant" (Box 20, Folder 18)
      - Duncan, Howard, "Kant, Buroker, and the Problem of Incongruent Counterparts" (Box 20, Folder 19)
      - Duncan, Howard, "Kant's Methodology: Progress Beyond Newton?" (2 drafts), 1985 (Box 20, Folder 20)
      - Duncan, Howard, "Constructions and Their Discovery", 1984 (Box 20, Folder 21)
      - Eells, Ellery, "Bayesian Epistemology: Probabilistic Confirmation and Rational Decision" (Box 21, Folder 1)
      - Essler, Wilhelm K., "Truth and Knowledge: Some Considerations Concerning the Task of Philosophy of Science" (Box 21, Folder 2)
      - Falkenstein, Lorne, "Kant's Argument for the Non-Spatiotemporality of Things in Themselves" (Box 21, Folder 3)
      - Fisette, David, ed., Consciousness and Intentionality: Models and Modalities of Attribution (Box 21, Folder 4)
      - Forster, Malcolm R., "Whewell's Consilience of Inductions and the Reality of Component Causes", 1986 (Box 21, Folder 5)
      - Forster, Paul D., "Kant, Boole, and the Origins of Peirce's Early Metaphysics" (Box 21, Folder 6)
      - Forster, Paul D., "The Unity of Peirce's Theories of Truth" (Box 21, Folder 7)
      - Foss, Jeffrey E., "The Logical and Sociological Structure of Science" (Box 21, Folder 8)
      - Falkenstein, Lorne, ed., Logic and the Workings of the Mind (Box 21, Folder 9)
      - "Faculty Psychology in Early Modern Philosophy," author unknown (Box 21, Folder 10)
      - Forster, Eckhart, "Is There a 'Gap' in Kant's Critical System?", 1985 (Box 21, Folder 11)
      - Friedman, Michael, "The Metaphysical Foundations of Newtonian Science" (3 drafts) (Box 21, Folder 12)
      - Friedman, Michael, "Preface" (translation), 1986 (Box 21, Folder 13)
      - Friedman, Michael, "Scientific Objectivity in Historical Perspective" (Box 21, Folder 14)
      - Friedman, Michael, "Kant on the Foundations of newtonian Science", 1984 (Box 21, Folder 15)
      - Friedman, Michael, "Kant's Theory of Geometry", 1984 (Box 21, Folder 16)
      - Friedman, Michael, "On the Transition from the Metaphysical Foundations of Natural Science to Physics", 1989 (Box 21, Folder 17)
      - Friedman, Michael, "Poincare's Conventionalism and the Logical Positivists" (Box 21, Folder 18)
      - Friedman, Michael, "Kant on Concepts and Intuitions in the Mathematical Sciences", 1987 (Box 21, Folder 19)
      - Giere, Ronald N., "On the Metaphilosophy of Science" (Box 21, Folder 20)
      - Good, Gregory, "Method, Science, and the Historical Approach: Were John Herschel's Optical Researches Guided by His Ideas on Method?", 1983 (Box 22, Folder 1)
      - Grier, Michelle Gilmore, "The Role of Transcendental Illusion in Kant's Account of Systematicity", 1993 (Box 22, Folder 2)
      - Grimes, Thomas R., "Scientific Realism and the Problem of Underdetermination" (Box 22, Folder 3)
      - Gruender, David, "Values and the Philosophy of Science" in Developments in the Theory of Science, ed. Gerhard Preyer and Alexander Ulfia (Box 22, Folder 4)
      - Hanson, Norwood Russell, "An Anatomy of Discovery" (Box 22, Folder 5)
      - Hanson, Norwood Russell, "Logical Positivism and the Interpretation of Scientific Theories" (Box 22, Folder 6)
      - Harper, William, "Isaac Newton on Empirical Success and Scientific Method" (Box 22, Folder 7)
      - Harper, William, "Newton's Phenomena", 1996 (Box 22, Folder 8)
      - Harper, William, "Newton, Isaac" (Box 22, Folder 9)
      - Harper, William et al., "Unification and Support: Harmonic Law Ratios Measure the Mass of the Sun" (2 drafts) (Box 22, Folder 10)
      - Harper, William, "Kant's Empirical Realism and the Second Analogy of Experience" (2 drafts + Butts' comments), 1980 (Box 22, Folder 11)
      - Harper, William, "Kant on the A Priori and Material Necessity" (Box 22, Folder 12)
      - Harper, William, "Kant on Incongruent Counterparts", 1987 (Box 22, Folder 13)
      - Harriot, Howard H., "R.A. Fisher and the Interpretation of Probability" (Box 22, Folder 14)
      - Heimann, P.M., "Force and Inertia: Euler and Kant's Metaphysical Foundations of Natural Science" (Box 22, Folder 15)
      - Hintikka, Jaakko, "Wittgenstein's Semantical Kantianism" (Box 22, Folder 16)
      - Hughes, R.J.G., "Laws of Physics, Laws of Nature, and the Representational Account of Theories" (Box 22, Folder 17)
      - "Inaugural Dissertation," author unknown (Box 23, Folder 1)
      - Jacquette, Dale, "Intentionality and the Myth of Pure Syntax" (Box 23, Folder 2)
      - Jobe, Evan, "Explanation, Causality, and Counterfactuals" (Box 23, Folder 3)
      - Juhl, Cory and Kelly, Kevin T., "Transcendental Deductions and Universal Architectures for Inductive Inference" (Box 23, Folder 4)
      - Kambartel, Friedrich, "Versuch uber das Verstehen" (Box 23, Folder 5)
      - Kitcher, Patricia, "Apperception and Epistemic Responsibility" (Box 23, Folder 6)
      - Kitcher, Phillip, "Projecting the Order of Nature" (3 drafts) (Box 23, Folder 7)
      - Kuehn, Manfred, "Kant's Conception of 'Hume's Problem'" (Box 23, Folder 8)
      - Kuhn, Thomas, "What are Scientific Revolutions" and "Commensurability, Comparability, Communicability" (Box 23, Folder 9)
      - Landry, Vicki Frappollo, "The Unconstituted Constitutor and the Essence of Poker" (Box 23, Folder 10)
      - Lariviere, D. Anthony, "On the Alleged Cartesianism of the Port-Royal Logic" (Box 23, Folder 11)
      - Laudan, Larry, "The Pseudoscience of Science?" (Box 23, Folder 12)
      - Laudan, Larry et al., "Testing Methodologies Against History", 1985 (Box 23, Folder 13)
      - Laudan, Larry, "Science at the Bar: Causes for Concern" (Box 23, Folder 14)
      - "Locke and the Received View of Dreams," author unknown (Box 23, Folder 15)
      - Lugg, Andrew, "Resolving Disagreement in Science" (Box 23, Folder 16)
      - Lugg, Andrew, "Stuff and Nonsense: Pseudoscience as Madness" (Box 23, Folder 17)
      - Lugg, Andrew, Review of "My Philosophical Development" by Bertrand Russell (Box 23, Folder 18)
      - Majer, Ulrich, "Simplicity and Distinctness: The Limits of Referential Semantics", 1988 (Box 23, Folder 19)
      - Matheson, Carl, "Observational Adequacy as Distinct from the Truth About Observables" (Box 23, Folder 20)
      - McMullin, Ernan, "The Rational and the Social in the History of Science" (Box 23, Folder 21)
      - Melmer, Arthur, "Space Time and Thought in Kant" (Box 24, Folder 1)
      - Metcalfe, John, Critical Notice on Menachem Fisch's "William Whewell: Philosopher of Science", 1992 (Box 24, Folder 2)
      - Meyer, Michel, "Why Did Kant Write Two Versions of the Transcendental Deduction?" (Box 24, Folder 3)
      - Mittelstrass, Jurgen, "Scientific Rationality and Its Reconstruction" (Box 24, Folder 4)
      - Montesano, Aldo, "Rationality in Economics: A General Framework" (Box 24, Folder 5)
      - Morrison, Margaret, "Whewell on the Ultimate Problem of Philosophy", 1996 (Box 24, Folder 6)
      - Moulines, C. Ulises, "Structuralism vs. Operationalism" (Box 24, Folder 7)
      - Nickels, Thomas, "What Is a Problem that We May Solve It?", 1980 (Box 24, Folder 8)
      - Niiniluoto, Ilkka, "Ernst Mach as a Philosopher of Science" (Box 24, Folder 9)
      - Okruhlik, Kathleen, "Kant on Realism and Methodology" (2 drafts) (Box 24, Folder 10)
      - Palter, Robert, "Kant's Idea of Absolute Space" (Box 24, Folder 11)
      - Peterson, Philip, "Theory and Meaning", 1968 (Box 24, Folder 12)
      - Preyer, Gerhard, "The Received View, Incommensurability, and the Comparison of Theories - Beliefs as the Basis of Theorizing" (Box 24, Folder 13)
      - Preyer, Gerhard and Ulfig, Alexander, "Semantic of Theoretical Language, Meaningful Measurement, and the Concept of Physical Law" (Box 24, Folder 14)
      - Rescher, Nicholas, "Leibniz Finds a Niche (Settling in at the Court of Hanover: 1676-1677)", 1991 (Box 24, Folder 15)
      - Rescher, Nicholas, "Meaningless Numbers", 1995 (Box 24, Folder 16)
      - Resnik, David, "Scientific Rationality and Epistemic Goals" (Box 24, Folder 17)
      - Rosenfield, Arthur H. and Trower, W. Peter, "Selected Works of Luis W. Alvarez With Commentary" (Box 24, Folder 18)
      - Rothbart, Daniel, "The Semantics of Metaphor and the Structure of Science", 1984 (Box 24, Folder 19)
      - Rothbart, Daniel, "Metaphor and the Growth of Scientific Knowledge" (Box 24, Folder 20)
      - Ruse, Michael, "A Philosopher's Day in Court: The Scopes Monkey Trial Revisited" (Box 24, Folder 21)
      - Schlesinger, Georg N., "Degrees of Characterization" (Box 24, Folder 22)
      - Schwartz, Robert, "Reflections on Projection" (Box 24, Folder 23)
      - Shea, William, "Filled With Wonder: Kant's Cosmological Essay, the Universal Natural History and Theory of the Heavens" (3 drafts) (Box 25, Folder 1)
      - Skyrms, Brian, "Evolution of Anomaly" (Box 25, Folder 2)
      - Stafleau, Marinus Dirk, "Theories Incorporated" (Box 25, Folder 3)
      - Tang, Paul C.L., "On Paul Churchband's Treatment of the Argument from Introspection and Scientific Realism" (Box 25, Folder 4)
      - Tang, Paul C.L. and Hildebrand, Erik A., "The Scientist Qua Scientist Must Be an Anti-Realist" (Box 25, Folder 5)
      - Thagard, Paul and Holyoak, Keith, "Discovering the Wave Theory of Sound: Inductive Inference in the Context of Problem Solving", 1985 (Box 25, Folder 6)
      - Tuschling, Burkhard, "Apperception and Ether: On the Idea of a Transcendental Deduction of Matter in Kant's Opus Postumum" (Box 25, Folder 7)
      - Unattributed Commentary on Butts' Work (Box 25, Folder 8)
      - Unidentified Typescript on Mach and Relativity (Box 25, Folder 9)
      - Van Kirk, Carol A., "Kant's Reply to Putnam" (Box 25, Folder 10)
      - Van Kirk, Carol A., "Kant and the Problem of Other Minds" (Box 25, Folder 11)
      - Van Cleve, James, "Reflections on Kant's Second Antimony", 1980 (Box 25, Folder 12)
      - Wheeler, Harvey, "The Invention of Modern Empiricism: The Juridicial Foundation of Francis Bacon's Philosophy of Science", 1983 (Box 25, Folder 13)
      - Will, F.L., "The Problem of Induction", 1968 (Box 25, Folder 14)
      - Wilson, David B., "A Physicist's Alternative to Materialism: The Religious Thought of George Gabriel Stokes" (Box 25, Folder 15)
      - Wilson, Fred, "Mill on the Operation of Discovering and Proving General Propositions" (Box 25, Folder 16)
      - Wilson, Fred, "Explanation, Causation, and Deduction" (Box 25, Folder 17)
      - Wilson, Fred, "Scottish Reason from Hume and Reid to Brown and Chalmers" (Box 25, Folder 18)
      - Wimsatt, William, "Von Baer's Law of Development, Entrenchment, and Scientific Change" (Box 25, Folder 19)
      - Wolters, Gereon, "Visionary Positivism: Ernst Mach's Philosophy of Science" (Box 25, Folder 20)
      - Reviews of Gereon Wolters' Mach I, Mach II, Einstein und die Relativitatstheorie (Box 25, Folder 21)
      - Wray, K. Brad, "Rational Communities" (Box 25, Folder 22)
      - Wray, K. Brad, "The Role of Solidarity in a Pragmatic Epistemology" (Box 25, Folder 23)
      - Wylie, Allison, "Philosophy of Archaeology" (Box 25, Folder 24)
      - Unidentified Manuscripts (Box 25, Folder 25)
  - Professional Correspondence, 1963-1997; 5.
    This subseries consists of general correspondence between Butts and his professional peers and colleagues. Material is arranged alphabetically by correspondent, including both individuals and organizations, and ranges from one letter to exchanges taking place over several years or decades, as with friend and colleague Jurgen Mittelstrass of the University of Konstanz.
    - Adams, Stephen J., 1995-1996 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Alexander von Humboldt Foundation, 1993-1995 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Anderson, E.O., 1986 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Baltas, Aristedes, 1992 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Barcus, Nancy B., 1982 (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - Bauer, Henry H., 1980-1986 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Beck, Lewis W., 1985 (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - Bentley, Margaret, 1974-1984 (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - Belgvad, Mogens, 1972-1973 (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - Brittan, Gordon, 1989 (Box 26, Folder 10)
    - Broughton, Roger, 1982-1983 (Box 26, Folder 11)
    - Buchdahl, Gerd, 1970-1989 (Box 26, Folder 12)
    - Bunge, Mario, 1980 (Box 26, Folder 13)
    - Bykov, A.N., 1981-1982 (Box 26, Folder 14)
    - Carrier, Martin, 1987 (Box 26, Folder 15)
    - Charpa, Ulrich, 1984 (Box 26, Folder 16)
    - Coelho, Victor, 1988-1992 (Box 26, Folder 17)
    - Cohen, H. Floris, 1993-1994 (Box 26, Folder 18)
    - Cohen, Robert S., 1973-1993 (Box 26, Folder 19)
    - Demopoulos, William, 1991 (Box 26, Folder 20)
    - Duchesneau, Francois, 1981-1985 (Box 26, Folder 21)
    - Earman, John, 1992 (Box 26, Folder 22)
    - Falkenstein, Lorne, 1987 (Box 26, Folder 23)
    - Finocchiaro, Maurice A., 1980 (Box 26, Folder 24)
    - Fisch, Max H., 1980 (Box 26, Folder 25)
    - Friedman, Michael, 1985 (Box 26, Folder 26)
    - Gavreau, Claude, 1980-1986 (Box 26, Folder 27)
    - Goudge, T.A., 1964 (Box 26, Folder 28)
    - Greene, John, 1982 (Box 26, Folder 29)
    - Grünbaum, Adolf, 1977-1995 (Box 26, Folder 30)
    - Gumanski, Leon, 1974 (Box 26, Folder 31)
    - Hacking, Ian, 1986 (Box 26, Folder 32)
    - Hallden, Soren, 1973 (Box 26, Folder 33)
    - Hintikka, Jaakko, 1975-1977 (Box 26, Folder 34)
    - Hiorth, Finngeir, 1973 (Box 26, Folder 35)
    - Hooker, Cliff, 1985-1988, 1994 (Box 26, Folder 36)
    - Hoven, Adrian van den, 1996 (Box 26, Folder 37)
    - Irvine, Andrew, 1982 (Box 26, Folder 38)
    - Janich, Peter, 1983 (Box 26, Folder 39)
    - Kaufmann, John C.E., 1997 (Box 26, Folder 40)
    - Keenan, C.W., 1964-1966 (Box 26, Folder 41)
    - Kendler, Howard H., 1980 (Box 26, Folder 42)
    - Kitcher, Philip, 1983, 1996 (Box 26, Folder 43)
    - Levere, Trevor H., 1980 (Box 26, Folder 44)
    - Lloyd, Elisabeth A., 1983 (Box 26, Folder 45)
    - Lugg, Andrew, 1985, 1992 (Box 26, Folder 46)
    - Martell, Charles, 1997 (Box 26, Folder 47)
    - Massey, Gerald, 1991-1994 (Box 26, Folder 48)
    - Mayo, Deborah G., 1986 (Box 26, Folder 49)
    - Mittelstrass, Jürgen, 1973-1978 (Box 26, Folder 50)
    - Mittelstrass, Jürgen, 1979-1995 (Box 26, Folder 51)
    - Nicholas, John M. (Nick), 1989 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Niiniluoto, Ilkka, 1985 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Ohruhlik, Kathleen, 1989 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Pagnini, Alessandro, 1991-1996 (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Parrini, Paolo, 1996 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Paterson, G.R., 1984-1986 (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Rescher, Nicholas, 1963-1996 (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Robson, Robert, 1963 (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - Ruse, Michael, 1982 (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - Rutherford, Don, 1990 (Box 27, Folder 10)
    - Sadovsky, Vadim, 1975-1982 (Box 27, Folder 11)
    - Savage, Wade, 1983-1986 (Box 27, Folder 12)
    - Savary, Claude, 1984-1986 (Box 27, Folder 13)
    - Shea, William (Bill), 1977-1992 (Box 27, Folder 14)
    - Stevens, Wesley, 1985-1993 (Box 27, Folder 15)
    - Stone, John M.R., 1987-1988 (Box 27, Folder 16)
    - Surette, Leon, 1982 (Box 27, Folder 17)
    - Theau, Jean, 1974 (Box 27, Folder 18)
    - Wahsner, Renate, 1991 (Box 27, Folder 19)
    - Weiner, Dora B., 1983-1984 (Box 27, Folder 20)
    - Wilson, David B., 1973 (Box 27, Folder 21)
    - Westfall, Richard, 1972 (Box 27, Folder 22)
    - Wolcott, Glenn, 1995 (Box 27, Folder 23)
    - Wolters, Gereon, 1981-1995 (Box 27, Folder 24)
    - Woolhouse, Roger, 1985-1988 (Box 27, Folder 25)
    - Miscellaneous and Unidentified Correspondence, 1963-1996 (Box 27, Folder 26)
    - Unsigned Fax from the University of Newcastle (Box 27, Folder 27)
    - Directory of Professional Contacts (Box 27, Folder 28)
- Multimedia, 1972-1997; III.; 32 Document Boxes
  The content of the materials in this series is mostly unknown, since they are largely stored on outdated multimedia formats that cannot currently be read by this department. The labels that Butts placed on his floppy disks, which appear to contain backups of his personal computer, indicate that some of the contents may be alternative drafts or supplemental materials to documents found in the paper portion of the collection (e.g. lectures, documentation from professional organizations). The most readily accessible materials are the audio cassette tapes, which mainly contain recordings of radio appearances that Butts made and dictated correspondence during the time of his hospitalization during the 1970s.